[ Music ]
［ 音乐 ］
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone, and
&gt;&gt; 早上好 各位
welcome to New Ways to Work with
欢迎来到玩转体能训练新方法
My name is Niharika [phonetic].
我是 Niharika
I'm an engineer on the Fitness
我是 Apple
team here at Apple, and today
健身团队的工程师
I'm going to be joined by my
来自我们健康团队的同事
colleague Karim, an engineer on
工程师 Karim
the Health team.
也将加入我们今天的话题
And we are so excited to share
我们非常兴奋地
with all of you some of the
与你们分享
brand-new features and
一些全新的特性与功能
capabilities that have been
它们已经随着 iOS 12
added to HealthKit in iOS 12 and
和 watchOS 5 加入了 HealthKit
Apple Watch was released 3 years
Apple Watch 发布于 3 年前
ago now, and since the
从那时起
beginning, our users have loved
我们的用户就热衷于
engaging with its health and
使用它的健康与
fitness features.
健身功能
They've loved closing their
他们喜欢完成每日任务圆环
rings and earning achievements,
及达成各种成就
sharing with their friends, but
并乐于和好友彼此分享
they've especially loved to do
但他们最喜欢的还是完成
workouts.
体能训练
And the watch has really become
虽然只是一个开始
just the beginning of what is a
但这块手表正在形成一个
vibrant, evolving ecosystem, and
充满活力 不断进化的生态系统
that is thanks to contributions
其中少不了在座各位
from developers like all of you.
开发人员的贡献
In just the last quarter of
仅仅 2017 年第四季度
2017, there were over 200
App Store 中
million downloads of apps in the
健康健美类别下的 App
Health and Fitness category on
下载量超过了 2 亿
the App Store, and that number
这是个惊人的数字
Two hundred million is so, so
两亿这个数字
cool.
实在太酷了
But more than that, it's a
更重要的是
testament to 2 things.
这证明了两件事
Number 1, it's a testament to
其一 它证明了你们各位开发人员的
the dedication all of you have
杰出贡献
shown in getting these great
为用户带来了绝佳的
user experiences out there.
产品体验
But number 2, it's a sign that
其二 这意味着人们在这一块
people really care.
有切实的需求
People are engaged in the space,
人们密切关注着这一领域
and they are so excited about
翘首期盼
what all of you are putting out
你们的新成果
And at the heart of this
这一生态系统的核心
ecosystem are these 2 apps,
是这两个 App
Activity and Health.
健身记录和健康
Activity is a home for you to
健身记录是为你呈现
visualize just that -- your
可视化运动数据的主界面
You can see your workouts.
你可以查看你的体能训练
You can see calories, exercise
查看热量消耗和锻炼时常
And Health is all of that and
健康 App 包括更多东西
And of course, at the heart of
当然 所有这些的核心
all of that, which is the reason
也就是我们今天
we're here today, is HealthKit.
齐聚于此的理由 就是 HealthKit
And so we have a ton of exciting
我们今天有海量激动人心的
things to talk about today, but
事情要讨论
before we get started with any
在我们开始那些话题之前
of that, we have to talk about
我们要先谈一谈
something extremely important,
一件极其重要的事
and that is privacy and
那就是隐私和授权
authorization, because data is
由于数据是相当敏感的
sensitive, especially health
尤其是健康数据
data, and it is so important to
因此在设计研发 App 时
make sure that you have a
确保有一个
comprehensive privacy story when
完整的隐私政策
working with your apps.
至关重要
Next, Karim is going to share
然后 Karim 会和大家分享
our brand-new workout features,
我们全新的训练功能特性
which have made it easier than
可以使你更加轻松地
ever before to develop a robust
打造一款可靠的
workout app.
体能训练 App
And lastly, I'm so excited to
最后 我激动地跟大家分享
share our new Quantity series
我们全新的 Quantity 系列 API
API, which is a brand-new way to
这是一个储存与关联
both store and relate
高频数据的
high-frequency data.
全新方式
So let's get started.
好 让我们开始吧
Like I mentioned, privacy and
正如我所提到
authorization has to come at the
隐私和授权必须
beginning of any development
先行于任何开发过程
story.
我们 Apple 看待隐私
privacy in 1 simple way: Privacy
有一条简单的原则
is about people.
隐私以用户为本
And HealthKit is designed with
HealthKit 就是以此为基础 设计而成的
HealthKit is designed to put
HealthKit 的设计使用户
users in control of their data.
成为数据的主人
Users have the ability to grant
用户可以授权访问
access as well as revoke
也可以随时取消授权
And as developers, all of you
作为开发人员的你们
are the last link of that
是这一环里的最后一块拼图
puzzle, and we want to make sure
我们想要确保
we are giving you the tools to
我们提供给你们的工具
And we think about this in a few
我们想了几条
simple rules.
简单的规则
Number 1 is this idea of
第一条是根据你 App 的功能
proportional collection, and
收集部分数据
this is the idea that you should
意思是说
only be collecting data relative
你应当根据 App 需求
to what your app needs.
仅收集必要的数据
And this isn't a fixed set of
当然这不是永远
data.
固定的数据
At the beginning, this amount
刚开始时 数量可能
might be small.
不会很多
As your use cases, as your
根据你的实际情况
features grow, the amount of
当你的功能特性增加时
data you need to collect might
你所需的数据也会更多
be more, but it is so important
但是按照当时的特定需求
that you only collect what you
来收集必要数据
need at a specific time.
是非常重要的
And second is the idea that
第二条是 HealthKit 的授权
change.
是可以更改的
And this one's a little nuanced.
这一条有些微妙
For example, if a user resets
比如说 如果用户重置了
their location and privacy data,
他们的位置与隐私数据
their location and privacy
位置与隐私设置
setting, it is so important for
你必须确保尊重
you to make sure you're honoring
他们的行为
that, and it is your
这是你们
responsibility to make sure you
应尽的义务
And the best way to do this is
最好的方式
to treat HealthKit as the source
是将 HealthKit 视作真实数据的
of truth because HealthKit will
唯一来源 因为 HealthKit
update to reflect that
会不断更新用户的
authorization status, and it is
授权状态
so important to make sure you
你必须保证不私藏
don't cache any of that and make
任何用户数据
sure you're always turning to
保证你永远只从 HealthKit
HealthKit to ask what data you
获取你所需的数据
have access to.
这一点尤为重要
And these 2 ideas can be
这两个想法
distilled into 3 simple rules.
可以被提炼成 3 条规则
And when we're thinking about
当我们涉及隐私与授权时
should ask for only what you
你应当仅取所需
need, only when you need it, and
仅在需要时索取
every single time you need it.
且每次都要单独索取
And in code, this is just as
在代码实现上
simple.
这同样简单
Let's say I'm creating a workout
如果我要做一个体能训练 App
app, and I'm just getting
开始着手做
started, and, of course, I need
理所当然
to start with privacy and
我需要先从隐私与
authorization.
授权下手
First, since I'm creating a
首先 由于我在创建
workout app, I want to share the
一个体能训练 App 我想要
workout type, so I explicitly
和 HealthKit 共享训练类型
declare that I'm going to be
所以我需要明确表明我需要
sharing the workout type.
共享训练类型
Next, since I'm just getting
接下来 因为我只是在起步阶段
started, I only have a few
我需要追踪的
things that I'm trying to track.
数据类型并不多
I want to be able to track my
我想追踪用户的
user's heart rate, calories, as
心率 热量消耗
well as distance walking and
还有步行与
running.
跑步的路程
And this is all I need right
现阶段我只需要这些
now, and so that's all I'm going
所以我就是我要请求的
to ask for.
全部数据
And lastly, on my healthStore, I
最后 在我的 HealthStore 上
request authorization for just
我仅请求以上这些数据的授权
that.
我请求要共享的类型
my types to read.
以及要读取的类型
And with these 3 simple steps,
通过以上三个简单的步骤
we can really make sure that we
我们就能切实地确保
are taking the steps necessary
我们为尊重用户隐私
to respect our user's privacy.
完成了必要的步骤
And privacy is so important
隐私如此重要
because great apps have great
越好的 App 越重视隐私
privacy, and it's so important
在开发伊始
that you give attention to this
时刻注意这一点
at the beginning of any
是至关重要的
And now that we have access to
现在我们就能访问
our users' data, I'm so excited
用户数据了
to introduce Karim [phonetic] to
我迫不及待地向大家介绍 Karim
tell you all about the brand-new
他会向大家展示全新的
workout features.
体能训练的功能特性
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
Thank you so much for joining us
感谢大家今天参加这个会议
I am really excited to tell you
我怀着激动的心情
all about the new workout API.
与你们分享全新的体能训练 API
If you're new to HealthKit,
如果这是你第一次接触 HealthKit
you'll see just how easy it is
你会发现它如此简单好用
to create a full-featured
让你能从零开始
workout app from scratch.
打造一款功能完善的训练 App
If, on the other hand, you have
另一方面 假如你
a workout app on the App Store,
在 App Store 已经拥有一款训练 App
we'll show you all of the great
你仍然能看到关于这个 API 的
new features of the API that
所有全新的功能特性
your app can benefit from.
让你的 App 获益匪浅
So let's dive in.
让我们深入了解一下
First, I would like to take a
首先我想先谈谈
look at the general workout app
通常情况下体能训练 App 的
life cycle.
生命周期
So let's say we're building a
假如说我们正在创建一个
workout app to track our users'
训练 App 来追踪用户的活动
activity, and the first step is
首先第一步
to set up the app.
是配置你的 App
So at this state here, we know
在这个阶段 我们知道
that the user wants to perform a
用户想要做体能训练
workout, the type of activity,
训练的具体类型
and we need to make sure that
我们需要确保
our UI is ready for that.
我们的 UI 已经就位
Once the setup is done, we can
一旦配置完成
go ahead and start the workout.
我们就能开始体能训练了
So after this point, the user
在这个阶段
will be actively working out.
用户会积极锻炼
And then, of course, after some
当然 过了一会
time, the user will want to end
用户会想要结束
the workout.
体能训练
And from there, we can save this
在那时 我们可以
workout and all of its
在 HealthKit 中保存
associated data in HealthKit.
这条健身记录以及相关数据
So this is the general life
这就是一款体能训练 App
cycle of a workout app.
通常的生命周期
Now, let's see what happens when
现在让我们观察一下用户
the user is active.
在活跃时都发生么什么
With your user interface at the
你通过交互界面与用户产生关联
center, one of the tasks that
这个过程中你想要
you want to accomplish is to
完成的任务之一
collect data that is relevant to
就是收集那些
the workout and displayed in
显示在用户界面的
your user interface.
训练数据
And you also want to make sure
你同时得确保
that the user can control the
用户可以掌控
state of the session so that the
训练过程的状态
user can pause or resume the
随时暂停或是继续训练
And if you're familiar with
如果你熟悉 HealthKit
HealthKit, you might know about
你可能了解
HKWorkoutSession on watchOS.
watchOS 上的 HKWorkoutSession
HKWorkoutSession allows you to
HKWorkoutSession 可以处理
handle a few of these steps in
生命周期中的某几个步骤
It will prepare the device's
它会使设备的传感器
sensors for data collection set
进入随时准备收集数据的状态
so that you can accurately
使你能够准确地
collect data that's relevant to
收集到训练相关的数据
the workout like calories and
比如热量消耗 或是心率
It will also allow your
它还能让你的 App
application to run in the
在训练进行时
background when the workout is
可以在后台运行
active.
你也能够用
HKWorkoutSession to control the
HKWorkoutSession 来控制
state of this, the workout.
这次训练的状态
And finally, you can also
以及最后 你可以
generate events like swimming
产生生成类似游泳
laps in segments.
圈数的活动
But of course, this is not
当然 这样还不够
enough, and you also need to
你还需要
collect data that is relevant to
收集训练过程中
the workout that's generated by
设备产生的数据
the device and be able to save
然后将它都保存到
it all in HealthKit.
HealthKit 上面
And to do just that, I'm really
为了实现这一点
happy to introduce a new class,
我很高兴介绍一个新的类
HKWorkoutBuilder.
HKWorkoutBuilder
The workout builder is your
这个 workout builder 是你
one-stop shop to collecting data
收集数据并将其保存在 HealthKit 中的
and saving it in HealthKit.
一站式解决方案
So the builder will create and
所以这个 builder 会创建
save an HKWorkout object, which
并存储一个 HKWorkout 对象
is a representation of a workout
它在 HealthKit 中代表了一次
in HealthKit.
体能训练
You can then add samples,
然后你可以在创建体能训练时
events, and also custom metadata
在 builder 中添加样本
to the builder while building
活动以及自定义的元数据
And if you're on watchOS, you
并且如果你在 watchOS 上
can use its subclass,
你可以使用它的子类
HKLiveWorkoutBuilder.
HKLiveWorkoutBuilder
So it's watchOS only, and
所以它仅限于 watchOS
because it's a subclass of the
而且又因为它是 HKWorkoutBuilder 的
workout builder, it has all of
子类 它有这个 builder 的
the great benefits of the
所有优点
builder, but because it's on
但又因为它在 watchOS 上
watchOS and it works closely
它和 HKWorkoutSession
with HKWorkoutSession, it has
紧密合作
all of these really cool
它有那些很酷的
features like automatic sample
功能 比如说自动样本
and event collection, which
自动活动收集
we'll talk about later.
我们之后会再说到
So let's go back to the workout
所以让我们回到体能训练的
app life cycle, and we'll see
App 的生命周期 我们会看到
how we can now set up and start
我们如何用新的 workout builder
the workout using the new
设置并开始体能训练
So first, we need to create a
那么首先 我们需要创建一个
And to do that, we use the
我们需要用一个初始化程序
initializer, and we have to pass
我们需要传入一个
a healthStore object, a
healthStore 对象
configuration which contains
一个配置项 包含
information like the workout
体能训练类型
type, whether it's indoor or
户内或户外
outdoor, and other information.
其他有关信息的
And finally, an optional device
最后 一个可选的设备
if the data comes from an
比如说如果数据来自
external device, for example.
一个外部的设备
Once my builder is created, all
一旦我的 builder 被创建
I need to do is call
我所需要做的就是
beginCollection and pass a start
调用 beginCollection 并且传入一个
date.
开始时间
It's that simple.
就是这么简单
If you are on watchOS, you can
如果你在 watchOS 上
use the live workout builder.
你可以用 HKLiveWorkoutBuilder
And so first, you need to create
首先 你需要创建一个
a workout session by passing the
体能训练 session
healthStore and
传入 healthStore 对象
workoutConfiguration, and then
以及 workoutConfiguration
you do not create the builder
然后你不要自己创建 builder
yourself, but you retrieve it
你可以直接
directly from the session by
从 session 中获取
using this call.
通过这次调用
Once we have the session and
一旦我们有了 session
builder, we can go ahead and
和 builder 我们可以继续
start them up.
并开始了
And so it's as easy as calling
调用 session 上的 startActivity
startActivity on the session and
和 builder 上的 beginCollection
beginCollection on the builder
传入一个开始时间
by passing a start date.
就是这么简单
So this is how you set up and
这就是如何用 builder
start a workout using the
设置并创建一个体能训练
Now, let's see how we can
现在 我们来看看我们如何
collect data displayed directly
收集直接展示
in our user interface and be
在用户界面上的数据
able to control the state of the
以及如何控制体能训练的状态
workout when the user requests
当用户需要它的时候
So to collect data, if we want
为了收集数据
to add samples that are relevant
如果我们想要添加与体能训练
to the workout, like calories,
有关的样本数据 比如卡路里
or distance, or heart rate, we
距离 心率
can do that using a very simple
我们可以调用一个简单的方法
call, builder.add, and give it
即 builder.add
an array of HKSamples.
给它传入一个 HKSample 数组
If we have events that we want
如果我们有想要添加到
to add to the workout, it's very
体能训练中的事件
similar.
也非常类似
We just call builder
我们只需调用
.addWorkoutEvents.
builder.addWorkoutEvents
For metadata, you guessed it.
至于元数据 你们肯定猜到了
With the dictionary of metadata,
有了元数据字典
we just call builder.addMetadata
我们只需调用 builder.addMetadata
and pass the dictionary.
然后传入字典即可
But on Apple Watch, because the
但是在 Apple Watch 上
device is on your wrist and has
因为设备是在手腕上
all this wide range of sensors,
而且有众多传感器
you can actually generate data
你可以产生真实的数据
like calories and distance.
比如卡路里和距离
And wouldn't it be cool if we
那么如果我们可以让 builder
could have all of this data
全自动地收集所有数据
automatically collected by the
岂不是很棒
Starting with watchOS 5, we now
从 watchOS 5 开始
have automatic data collection,
我们有了自动数据收集
and it all starts with
这一切从
HKLiveWorkoutDataSource.
HKLiveWorkoutDataSource 开始
So the data source will collect
所以这个数据源会
samples that are relevant to the
收集与当前体能训练相关的
workout currently running.
体能训练相关的样本数据
You do, however, have the option
不过 你仍然可以选择
which types you want to collect,
你想要收集的类型
so you can add or remove types
你可以添加或移除类型
as you wish.
只需根据你的需求
And this is how it works.
它的工作方式如下
First, we create a data source.
首先 我们创建一个数据源
And here, I pass the healthStore
在这 我传入了 healthStore
as well as the
同时也传入了 workoutConfiguration
And since I'm passing the
由于我传入的配置
configuration that contains
包含了活动类型
information about the activity
的有关信息
type, the data source will be
数据源从而能够
able to infer which types should
推断针对这次体能训练
be collected for this workout.
应该收集哪些类型的数据
Next, I simply need to set the
接下来 我只需把
data source on the live workout
数据源设置在 live workout builder 上面
And optionally, you can add or
以及可选地 你可以增加
remove types that are being
或移除正在收集的类型
So let's say I want to add the
比如说我想要
type.
添加类型
I can specify which type I want
我可以指明
to add here as well as an
我想在这里添加的类型
optional predicate if I want to
如果我想要进一步
further limit which types are
限制被收集的类型
being collected.
也可以指明一个可选的谓词
And finally, we just call
最后 我们只需调用 dataSource
dataSource.
.collectStatistics
collectStatistics for and pass
传入类型
the type as well as the
同样还有 optionalPredicate
So now that we have data being
那么现在数据正在被收集
collected, let's see how we can
我们来看看如何可以将其
display it directly in our user
直接显示在用户界面上
So every time new data comes in
每次 builder 的委托方法
the builder's delegate method,
带来新数据
workout builder did collect data
workoutBuilder 的
of collected types will be
didCollectDataOfcollectedTypes
called.
会被调用
And so here, if, for example,
那么在这里 比如说如果
I'm interested in the heart rate
我对心率类型感兴趣
type, I will make sure that it's
我会确保它是
one of the collected types.
被收集的数据类型之一
And then, I simply make use of
然后 我只需利用
the builder's statistics for
用 builder 的针对数量类型的
quantity type method, which
数据方法
gives me an HKStatistics object
它会返回一个 HKStatistics 对象
that will contain information,
其中包含了相关信息
in this case, like minimum,
在这个例子中 有最小值
maximum, average, as well as
最大值 平均值 以及
most recent value for the heart
在此次体能训练中
rate that's recorded throughout
最近记录的心率数值
From there, I can simply update
这样 我就可以
my user interface.
更新用户界面了
One thing that's also very
在体能训练类 App 中
common in workout apps is to
表示时间流逝的计时器
have an elapsed timer.
非常常见
And so, of course, we start the
所以 当然 我们要在
timer at the beginning of the
训练开始时开始
workout, but that's not enough
计时 但这并不够
because pause or resume events
因为暂停或继续事件会
will affect duration of the
影响训练持续
workout.
时间的计算
So every time new events are
所以每当新活动
added to the builder, the
被添加进 builder
builder's delegate method
builder 的委托方法
workoutBuilderDid CollectEvents
workoutBuilderDidCollectEvents
will be called.
就会被调用
And from here, you can simply
这样 你就可以
use the builder's elapsedTime
用 builder 的 elapsedTime
property, which will give you
属性 它会告诉你
the current elapsed time for the
此体能训练当前已
workout.
持续的时间
It's that easy.
就这么简单
Next, let's see how we can
接下来 我们看看
control the state of the
如何控制训练的状态
So first, I'd like to talk about
首先 我想要讨论一下
all of the different states that
训练 session 里
the workout session can be in.
所有的不同的状态
And the first one is Not
第一个是 Not Started
So here, the workout has not
这意味着训练还没有开始
started yet, and we're not yet,
我们还没有 哦不
the user is not performing the
用户还没有开始体能训练
workout.
在这之后 我们会转到
to the Prepared state.
Prepared 状态
And so the Prepared state will
Prepared 状态会让系统
put the system in Session Mode,
处于 Session 模式下
which means that your
意味着你的 App
application will have background
会有后台运行能力
running, the sensors will also
传感器也会做好
be ready to track the activity,
追踪活动的准备
but the workout has not started
但是训练还未开始
So if you, for example, have a
比如说 如果你的 App
countdown in your app before a
在训练前有一个倒数秒
workout, you can move the
你可以在这之前将 session
session to the Prepared state
置为 Prepared 状态
before that to make sure that
以此来确保
the device is ready to start
设备已经准备好
tracking the activity.
开始追踪活动
After that, we can move to the
在这之后 我们可以转到 Running 状态
And here, the user is actively
这时 用户在积极地
working out.
进行体能训练
And of course, the user can move
当然 用户也可以
to the Paused, back to Running,
变成 Paused 然后回到 Running
and back and forth between these
然后在两者之间来回切换
2 until the workout is Stopped.
直到训练结束
So here, the device is still in
这时 设备仍然处于
Session Mode, which means that
Session 模式下 意味着
your app is still running in the
你的 App 仍然在后台运行
background, so that gives you
这就为你争取了
some extra time that, if you
一点额外时间 让你需要的话
needed to save the workout.
可以保存这次体能训练
After that, we can simply end
这之后 我们就可以结束
the workout.
体能训练了
And from there, the system will
从这起 系统就会
exit Session Mode.
退出 Session 模式
And to be able to move between
想要在这些状态之间
all these states, you simply
切换 你只需
need to use these calls directly
在体能训练 session 上
on the workout session.
调用这些
So that's how we can collect
这就是我们收集
data displayed in our user
用户界面展示数据
interface as well as control the
以及控制
state of the session.
session 状态的方式
Let's see now how we can end the
我们来看看如何
workout and save it in
结束体能训练并且将其保存在
HealthKit.
HealthKit 中
So to end the workout, you first
为了结束体能训练
call session.end, and then you
首先调用 session.end
also call builder.
同时调用 builder.endCollection
endCollection and pass the
传入体能训练的
workout's end date.
结束时间
At this point, no data is going
在这一时间点 尚未有
to be collected for this
任何有关此体能训练的数据被收集
workout.
数据被收集
And then, if you want to save
然后 如果你想把体能训练
the workout in HealthKit, you
保存在 HealthKit 中
just call builder.
你直接调用 builder.finishWorkout
finishWorkout, and you will get
然后你会在
back a workout object in the
completion handler 中得到一个
completion handler that's
体能训练对象
already saved in HealthKit with
与它相关的数据已经被
all of its associated data.
保存在 HealthKit 中了
So that's how you now build a
这就是现在使用新的 API
workout app using the new API.
创造一个体能训练 App 的方式
And now, I'd like to show you
接下来 我想要
how this all works in a demo
用一个样本来演示一遍
where we will be building a
我们会在 demo 中创建一个
workout app for Apple Watch.
为 Apple Watch 设计的体能训练 App
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
So I'm actually currently
我目前实际上
building a workout app that will
正在写一个
allow my users to track running
让用户记录跑步的
workouts.
体能训练 App
And it's a very simple app.
它是个非常简单的 App
I have a big Run button here.
这里有一个大的 “Run” 按钮
When I tap on it, I'm presented
当点击它时 我会
with this user interface that
显示这样一个界面
will show an elapsed time of
其中会显示此次训练的
their workout as well as some
逝去时间以及一些
metrics, like calorie burned,
其他指标 比如消耗的卡路里
the most recent heart rate, as
最近心率
well as the distance that's run
还有在这次训练中
in the workout.
已经跑的距离
Of course, my user will have the
当然 用户也
option to control the state of
可以控制训练的状态
the workout, so my user can
因此 用户可以
pause, resume, and end the
暂停 继续 以及结束
workout.
体能训练
So I already went ahead and
实际上我已经提前
implemented the user interface.
写好了这些用户界面
So all that's left for me now is
剩下的是
to use the new workout API and
使用新的体能训练 API
make my app functional.
让我的 App 可以跑起来
And the first thing that we need
我们要做的第一件事
to do here is make sure that the
就是确保
project is properly set up.
这个项目的设置是正确的
And so to do that, I'm going to
想要做到这个 我准备前往
head over to my Project
我的项目设置页面
Settings, go to the Capabilities
然后打开
tab, and here just make sure
Capabilities 标签页 确保
that the HealthKit Capability is
这里的 HealthKit Capability
turned on.
处于开启状态
And you should also do the same
同时针对你的 WatchKit App 扩展
for your WatchKit app extension.
也需要做相同的事
So again, make sure that the
所以再一次 确保
HealthKit Capability is turned
HealthKit Capability 是开启的
Once I did that, we should also
当我完成了这些 我们也应该
add the 2 purpose strings in the
把这两个目的字符串添加在
info.plist file that will tell
info.plist 文件中
my users why I need access to
以告知我的用户我为什么需要
their health data.
访问他们的健康数据
And so here, the first string is
这里的第一条字符串是
"health share user description"
“Health Share Usage Description”
that tells my users why I would
告诉用户我为什么
like to save data in HealthKit
想要把数据存储在 HealthKit 中
as well as help update usage
同时帮助更新
description.
用户描述
That will tell them why I need
它会告诉用户为什么我
to read data in HealthKit.
需要读取 HealthKit 中的数据
Once that's done, I can now
完成了这些 现在我可以
start using the new workout API.
开始使用新的体能训练 API
And of course, the first step
当然 使用 API 的
before being able to use the API
前提条件是
is to make sure that I request
确保我请求了我需要的
authorization for the data that
数据的相关授权
And so, of course, every app is
当然 每个 App
different.
都是不同的
And in my case, if we go back to
在这次例子中 如果我们回到
my application, I will be saving
我的 App 我会保存
a workout here.
一个体能训练
So that's one of the types that
所以这是我需要
I will be needing access to.
有权限访问的类型之一
And I also need to be able to
另外 我也需要能够
read calories, heart rate, as
读取卡路里 心率
well as distance.
还有距离
So let's do that.
咱们来做这些
And of course, we need to make
当然 我们需要确保
sure that we always ask for
当我们真正需要授权的时候
authorization when we need it.
才发起请求
In my case here, I want to do
在我的例子中
that every time the user is
我需要在每次用户看到这个 UI 时
presented with this UI so that I
来请求 这样我可以
can make sure that I have the
确保我获得了
authorization before starting a
我获得了相关的授权 在开始
workout.
体能训练前
So this view here is backed by
所以这里的这个视图
my workoutStartView Watchkit
由 WorkoutStartView 的
interface controller, and I'm
WKInterFaceController 控制
going to go ahead and implement
那我准备在 didAppear 方法中
the authorization in the
来执行授权
So first, my typesToShare here
所以首先 我这里的 typesToShare
is workout because I want to be
应该是 workout 因为我希望
able to save a workout at the
在最后可以保存一个
end.
体能训练
Next, I would like to read
接下来 我希望读取
heartRate, activeEnergyBurned,
心率 动态卡路里
as well as
同时还有步行 + 跑步距离
Once I have my typesToShare and
一旦设置好了 typesToShare
typesToRead, I just need to call
和 typesToRead 我只需在
requestAuthorization on the
healthStore 上调用 requestAuthorization
healthStore and pass the types.
并且传入这两个类型
So let's go ahead and run this
那么我们现在来运行
code now and see what happens.
一下这个代码看看会发生什么
And because the watch screen is
而且因为 Apple Watch 的屏幕
small, the user will be
比较小 用户会在
presented with an authorization
手机上看到一张
sheet on the phone.
授权表单
So you need to make sure to also
所以你需要确保
handle authorization on your
在你的 iPhone App 上也能
iPhone app.
处理授权
Going to go ahead and dismiss
那我们继续
this view here.
先关闭这个视图
And so let's open my iPhone app.
那么我们现在打开我的 iPhone App
And here, I'm presented with an
这里 我看到了一张
authorization sheet where I can
授权表单 在这我可以决定
decide if I want to grant this
我是否授予这个 App
application access or not.
访问权限
For the purpose of this demo,
对于现在这个样本
I'm going to turn all the
我会把所有类别都打开 并且点击“允许”
And that's how we have now
这就是如何给我的 App
granted the authorization to my
授予访问权限
Next, we can now finally get
接下来 我们终于可以开始
started with the workout API.
用体能训练 API 了
So when I tap on this button
所以当我点击这里的这个按钮
here, this view will be passed,
这个视图会被传过来
all the workoutConfiguration
包含体能训练
object that contains information
相关信息的
about the workout.
workoutConfiguration 对象
In this instance here, it's a
在这个例子中
running workout.
这是个跑步训练
And from there, I can go ahead
从那里 我可以继续
and set up my workout.
设置我的体能训练了
So this view here is backed by
这个视图由
my workout session, WatchKit
我的体能训练 session
interface controller, and I'm
WatchKit 界面控制器支持
going to go do the setup in the
我会在唤醒方法中
awake method.
完成设置
So first, I'm going to create
那么首先 我会创建
the HKWorkoutSession as well as
HKWorkoutSession 和
the HKLiveWorkoutBuilder.
HKLiveWorkoutBuilder
So we create the session using
我们用初始化程序
its initializer, and we pass the
创建了 session
workout configuration to it.
我们再把体能训练配置对象传给它
From there, we simply retrieve
然后 我们只需从 session 中
the builder directly from the
直接获取 builder
session.
如果体能训练配置项无效
the workout configuration is
创建 session 可能会失败
invalid, so that's why I wrap my
所以这就是为什么我会
code here in a do-catch block
把这段代码放在一个 do-catch 区块中
and dismiss if I have any
如果有任何错误 会被忽略
Next, let's set up the session
接下来 让我们设置这个 session
and builder.
和 builder
So in this case, I want my
在这个例子中
interface controller to be the
我希望我的界面控制器
delegate of both the session and
可以是 session 和
the builder.
builder 的委托
And because I also want to
因为我也想
collect samples generated by the
收集设备产生的采样数据
device, I'm going to use here a
我需要在这里使用
live data source and pass it a
一个实时的数据源并且传给它
workout configuration so that
一个体能训练配置项
the types are automatically
这样各种类型就会
inferred for me.
为我自动推断出来
Finally, I simply start the
最后 我只需
session as well as the builder.
启动 session 和 builder
So now that my workout is
那么既然我的体能训练已经
started, the first thing that I
开始 我需要做的第一件事
need to do is to start my
就是启动我的
elapsedTime timer.
elapsedTime 计时器
And so I'm going to do that here
我会在 beingCollectionCall 的
in the callback of the
回调中来
beingCollectionCall.
完成这个
I have a method here that will
我这里有一个方法
do that for me.
可以帮我做
And of course, because pause and
当然 因为暂停和
resume events can also affect
继续事件也会影响
the duration, I'm going to have
持续时间的计算 我在
this call in the builder's
builder 的 didCollectEvent 中
didCollectEvent call as well.
也需要调用这个
Now, let's implement this
现在 我们来实现这个方法
So in my UI, I'm using a
所以在我的 UI 中
WatchKit interface timer.
我使用了一个 WKInterfaceTimer
If you're not familiar with this
如果你对这个对象不熟悉
object, this object needs a date
这个对象需要一个
in the past from which it will
过去时间 然后从那个时间
start counting from.
开始计时
So I'm going to go ahead and
所以我接下来会
create my date object using the
用 builder 的 elapsedTime 属性
builder's elapsedTime property.
来创建我的时间对象
And because I want the date to
因为我想要的时间是
be in the past, I'm going to
过去时间 我需要
make sure that I have a minus
确保这里
sign here.
有一个负号
Next, I simply dispatch on the
接下来 我只需在主队列上
main queue because I'm doing UI
调度因为我在做 UI 方面的工作
work, and then I just set the
然后我只用在计时器上
date on the timer.
设置时间
I also need to make sure that
我也需要确保
the timer is only running when
计时器只在
the session is running as well.
session 运行的时候运行
So let's do that.
让我们来做这个
First, I grab the session state,
首先 我拿到 session 状态
and then, again, I dispatch on
然后 再一次我
the main queue.
在主队列上调度
And if the session is running,
如果 session 正在运行
I'm going to start the timer.
我会启动计时器
And if it's not, I'm going to
如果不在运行
call Stop on the timer.
我就停止计时器
And that's all you need to do to
这是你所需要做的
get the timer tracking the
让计时器追踪已用时长的
elapsed time.
全部事情
Next, let's make sure that our
接下来 我们来确保
metrics displayed in the UI are
我们在 UI 上展示的所有指标
also accurate.
也是准确的
So every time new samples are
所以每次 builder 收集到
collected by the builder, this
新的样本数据
method here will be called.
这里的这个方法会被调用
And so here, I'm just going to
那么这里 我也只需要
go and iterate over the
重复这里的
collectedTypes.
collectedTypes
And, in my case, all of the data
而且 在我的例子中 所有我需要的
that I'm interested in is
数据都是
quantity samples.
数量型样本
So I'm going to make sure that I
所以我要确保我
only handle those.
只处理这些
And from there, we can make use
从这里 我们可以利用
of the new builder's method,
针对数量数据的 builder 的新方法
builder.statistics, for quantity
builder.statistics
types, which will give me an
它会返回给我一个
HKStatistics object that
HKStatistics 对象
contains information like
包含了每个数据类型的最小值
minimum, maximum, average, and
最大值 平均值
most recent values for each
以及最近值
So I grab the statistics object
所以我拿到这个统计对象
here, and from there, I have a
从这 我有一个已经实现过的方法
implemented that will give me
会返回给我
the user interface label for
针对特别的数量类型的
this particular quantity type.
用户界面标签
And from there, it just update
它会用统计对象
my label using the statistics
更新我的标签
Next, let's make sure that we
接下来 我们来确保
can control the state when the
当用户需要的时候我们
user requests it.
可以控制状态
So every time my user will tap
所以每当用户轻点
the Pause button, this method
暂停按钮 这个方法
here will be called.
会被调用
And from there, I simply need to
这样 我只需
call session.pause.
调用 session.pause
For resume, it's very similar.
对于继续 也很类似
I'm going to do session.resume.
我会执行 session.resume
And finally, to end the workout,
以及最后 为了结束体能训练
we're going to call session.end
我会调用 session.end
and then builder.endCollection
再调用 builder.endCollection
and pass the workout's end date.
然后传入体能训练的结束时间
And from there, we're just going
然后 我们只需
to call finishWorkout to
调用 finishWorkout
actually save the workout and
来真正把这次体能训练
all of its associated data in
和所有相关数据保存
HealthKit.
在 HealthKit 中
And then, we just dismissed it
然后 我们只需要无视它
So let's go ahead and run this
那么我们来运行这段代码
code and see what happens now.
看看现在会发生什么
So I'm going to go ahead and
那么我来
start my workout here.
启动我的体能训练
And as we see now, I have my
如我们所看到的
timer updating.
我的计时器在更新
I have data directly collected
我的数据由 builder 直接
by the builder and displayed
收集并且在我的
right in my user interface.
用户界面上展示
And of course, I can also react
当然 我也可以响应
to the state changes, so going
状态变化 所以现在
to go ahead and pause the
来暂停这次体能训练
workout.
体能训练
My timer has paused.
计时器暂停了
Data collection as well.
数据采集也暂停了
I can resume.
我可以继续
And just like that, with a few
就像这样 只用几行代码
lines of code, I now have a
现在我有了一个
fully functional workout app.
全功能的体能训练 App
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
So I'm going to stop the workout
我现在准备停止体能训练
now, and let's see what we have
我们来看看我们在
just saved in the health app on
iPhone 的健康 App 中
the iPhone.
保存了什么
So this is my workout here that
这就是我刚刚保存的
I have just saved, and we have
体能训练 而且现在我们看到
now a very rich representation
直接保存在 HealthKit 中的体能训练
of this workout saved directly
有非常丰富的
in HealthKit.
信息展示
I have the device details as
我有设备的详细信息
well as all of the samples that
还有相关的所有样本
were associated, like heart
比如心率
rate, distance, and active
距离 活动能量
energy, and, also, the workout
还有当我暂停和
events that were generated when
继续 session 时
I paused and resumed the
产生的体能训练活动
And that's how easy it is now to
现在在 Apple Watch 上创建
build a full-featured workout
一个全功能的体能训练 App
app on Apple Watch.
就是这么简单
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
But of course, sometimes things
不过当然 有时候
don't go as planned.
事情并不像我们计划的那样
Let's say I'm running my first
比如说我在跑我的第一个
marathon and I'm really excited
马拉松 我特别激动
about it and using my favorite
在用我最喜欢的体能训练 App
workout app to track this
来追踪这次马拉松
marathon, but I only realize at
而我在最后才发现
the end that the app actually
这个 App 在途中的某个时候
crashed sometime in the middle,
居然崩溃了
making me lose all of this data.
搞得我失去了所有的数据
Well, with watchOS 5, we are
好吧 在 watchOS 5 中
introducing workout recovery
我们带来了体能训练恢复
that will solve that problem for
可以帮你解决这个问题
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
If your application happens to
如果你的 App 恰好
crash during an active workout,
在一次活跃的体能训练中崩溃
we will automatically relaunch
我们会自动重启你的 App
it and give it a chance to
给它一个恢复
recover the workout.
体能训练的机会
The workout session as well as
体能训练 session 和 builder
the builder will be recovered in
会以之前的状态恢复
their previous state, so you
所以你不应该在 builder 上
should not call startActivity or
调用 startActivity 或者
beginCollection on the builder.
beginCollection
If you are using a data source
如果你在使用一个
to automatically collect data,
自动收集数据的数据源
you do need to set it up again,
你需要重新设置它
and this is how it works.
下面是它的工作原理
If your app is relaunched after
如果你的 App
a crash, we will be calling the
在一次崩溃后重启 我们会调用
WatchKit extension delegate
WKExtensionDelegate 方法
method, handleActive
handleAcitiveWorkoutRecovery
From there, you simply need to
这样 你只需创建一个 healthStore 对象
then call recoverActive Workout
然后调用 recoverActiveWorkoutSession
Session, and you will get back a
然后你会在
session in the completion
completion handler 中拿回
handler.
一个 session
It's that simple.
就这么简单
So this is our new workout API.
这就是我们新的体能训练 API
It makes it easier than ever to
它让创造优秀的体能训练 App
build great workout apps.
变得前所未有的简单
We also have a new Quantity
我们也有一个新的
series API.
数量系列 API
And for that, I'd like to hand
有关这个 我想把麦克风
it back to my colleague Niharika
交还给我的同事 Niharika
to tell you more about it.
她会告诉你们更多有关它的信息
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; Isn't that incredible?
&gt;&gt; 刚才那些是不是好到难以置信
In less than 10 minutes, Karim
在不到 10 分钟的时间里
was able to build a fully
Karim 能够创建一个
functional workout app.
全功能的体能训练 App
And this is so important
这非常重要
because, like I mentioned
因为 像我刚才提到的
earlier, our users love doing
我们的用户喜爱做
workouts.
体能训练
And with these workouts come a
而这些体能训练会带来
lot of data.
相当多的数据
Let's say I'm interested in
比如说我想要
making a soccer app.
做一个足球 App
I really want to understand
我非常想弄清楚
exactly how my users are moving,
我的用户到底是如何运动的
and I want to track the distance
而且我想追踪在一次体能训练中
they're moving as they go side
他们在球场上
to side, across the field during
从一边跑到另一边时
the duration of a workout.
移动的距离
And what happens when we start
当我们开始体能训练时
the workout is that samples
样本数据就
start coming in.
开始产生了
My user first goes 2.25.
我的用户先跑了 2.25
They then go 1.6.
然后 1.6
They go a little more.
然后又跑了一点
And then, they finish it off.
然后 结束了
And in the past, each one of
从前 这里的每个
these distances would be stored
距离都会被存储为
as 1 individual HKQuantity
一个单独的 HKQuantity 样本
Each one would be independent,
每一个都是独立的
and they would be stored
而且会被分开储存
And so we thought that, wouldn't
我们考虑一下
it be great if you could
如果你可以有
actually just have 1 sample that
一个追踪累计总数的样本
tracks that cumulative total but
但同时其背后仍然有那些
is still backed by those
独立的数量支持
individual quantities behind it?
是不是很棒
And that's why we've introduced
这就是为什么我们引入了
HKCumulative
HKCumulative
QuantitySeriesSample, which is a
QuantitySeriesSample 它是一个
brand new sample type that
全新的样本类型
allows you to more efficiently
让你可以更高效地
store high-frequency data, and
存储高频数据
it's great for 2 reasons.
它很棒 有两个原因
Number 1, you only have to store
原因一 你只需要存储
1 sample that is backed by
一个由多个数量支撑的
multiple quantities, and so
样本 因此
you're more efficiently storing
你可以更高效地存储
the high-frequency data that
那些来自体能训练的
comes from things like workouts.
高频数据
And number 2, you now have a
第二 你现在
sense of connection between the
可以知道组成一个样本的
quantities that make up a
多个数量与样本本身的联系
So our new quantity series
因此我们新的 QuantitySeriesSample
sample is a subclass of
是 HKQuantitySample 的
HKQuantitySample, which some of
子类 你们中也许
you may already be familiar
有些人已经很熟悉
And if you've interacted with
如果你之前用过
HKQuantitySample before, our new
HKQuantitySample 我们新的
sample type will be very much
样本类型
the same.
基本上一样
So why would you want to use
那么为什么你想要
this?
用这个呢
Let's say you're interested in
比方说你想要
data visualization.
数据可视化
Your app requires complex
你的 App 需要复杂的
charting or graphs, and you're
图表或图形
trying to really visualize the
你正努力用
data that your users have in a
一种漂亮的方式可视化
beautiful way.
用户的数据
We actually suggest that you
实际上我们建议
continue using our
你继续使用我们的
HKStatisticsQuery or our
HKStatisticsQuery 或者
HKStatistics CollectionQuery.
HKStatisticsCollectionQuery
And that's because those are
这是因为那些类正是
preexisting queries that do just
已有的 query 中
this.
做这件事的
You have access to really
你有权访问到
fine-grained, rich data, and
真正详细的丰富的数据
these queries will already get
而这些 query 将会
the fine-grained data on our new
在新的系列样本上
series samples, so you won't
得到详细的数据 所以你无需
have to do any extra work to get
做任何额外的工作来获得
those details.
那些详细信息
If, for example, you're
如果 比方说
interested in data analysis, you
你想要做数据分析
want to go 1 step deeper.
你要更进一步
You want to understand the
你想要弄清楚
actual quantities that make up a
组成一个样本的
sample.
实际数据
We suggest you use our new
我们建议你使用我们新的
series sample query.
系列样本 query
And lastly, if you're like me
最后 如果你和我一样
and have a soccer app [laughs]
有一个足球 App [ 笑声 ]
or any app that has really
或者任何会高频
high-frequency data collection,
收集数据的 App
we suggest that you use our new
我们建议你使用我们新的
Quantity series sample builder,
数量系列样本 builder
which is a brand-new way for you
它作为一种全新的方式 让你
to actually be able to create
能够真的创建
those new cumulative Quantity
那些新的累计的
series samples and store that
数量系列样本 并且
data in a more efficient way.
以更有效率的方式存储数据
So let's start with our sample
那么让我们开始 sample query 吧
query.
像我刚提到的
for you to be able to really
你可以通过这种方式来
look deeper and understand the
看得更深入并且真正理解
individual HK quantities that
组成一个数量系列样本的
make up a Quantity series
独立的 HK 数量
And in code, we, of course,
在代码里 当然 我们
first want to start with
首先想要搞清楚
figuring out where we're going
我们会把这些新的数量
to store our new quantities.
存储在哪里
In my case, I'm going to store
在我的例子中 我会把它
it in an array of quantities.
存在一个数量的数组中
We next want to initialize our
接下来我们初始化 query
We initialize it with the sample
我们用我们感兴趣的样本
that we're interested in.
来初始化它
And in our completion handler is
我们的完成处理器
where the bulk of the work
正是这部分工作
happens.
进行的地方
In my case, I have a method
在我的例子中 我有一个
called analyzeQuantity which is
叫做 analyzeQuantity 的方法
going to do the work that I'm
会来完成我想要对数量
interested in with the quantity.
做的事情
In my case, that's adding it to
就是把它添加到
the array of quantities that I
刚才我声明的
declared earlier.
数量数组中
And lastly, we execute our
最后 我们来执行 query
It's really that simple.
就是如此简单
For those of you familiar with
你们中有人熟悉我们的
some of our other queries, this
其他的一些 query
behaves in a very similar way.
这里的表现非常相似
Next, we have our Quantity
接下来 我们有
series sample builder, which,
QuantitySeriesSampleBuilder
like I mentioned, is really
如我刚才提到的
great for apps that do have
对于那些会产生
high-frequency data ingestion
高频数据的 App 非常有用
because it's a more efficient
因为用这种方式
way to store that data but also
存储数据效率更高
allows you to kind of create
而且还允许你
connections between that.
创建它们之间的联系
So first, we, of course, want to
那么首先 当然
start with creating our sample
我们从创建样本 builder 开始
We initialize with the
我们用 HealthStore
healthStore and we initialize it
配合我们感兴趣的
with the quantityType that we're
quantityType 来初始化
Next, for whatever cadence
接下来 无论你希望用
you're interested in inserting
什么样的频率来插入
samples, you do that.
样本 你只管做
Let's use my soccer app as an
那么以我这个足球 App 为例
I am super interested in the
我非常需要
actual distances that my users
我的用户移动的
are moving, so I'm going to
实际距离 所以我要
declare the meter unit as the
声明这个测量单位
quantity that I'm interested in,
是我想要的数量
and I insert that into my
并且把它插入在
seriesBuilder.
seriesBuilder 中
And at the end, we call finish
最后 我在我的系列上
on my series, and we're actually
调用结束 然后我们实际上
going to get the new Quantity
会得到新的数量系列样本
series sample and be able to
并且能够来储存它 用一种
efficient way.
更有效的方式
And so we're really, really
因此 我们真的真的
excited for you to start
为你们感到激动
implemented our new Quantity
你们可以开始在新的
series APIs in your apps because
Quantity series API 上实现你们的 App 了
it's a brand-new way to store
因为这种全新的方式存储
your data more efficiently, and
数据更高效
its ability to be able to relate
而它将数据关联在一起的
data together really allows for
能力让一些有趣的分析
some interesting analysis.
成为了可能
So we have talked about a lot of
那么我们已经讨论了很多
interesting things, and we think
有意思的事情
that the best way to think about
我们认为考虑这些事情最好的方式
them is actually as parts of a
应该是用更完整的角度来看待
whole because together they
因为这些东西整合在一起
really make up a way for you to
真的可以让你
respect your users' user
从开始到结束都
experience from start to finish.
更加重视你的用户的体验
Of course, we have to start with
当然 我们必须开始
respecting user privacy.
尊重用户的隐私
Our users are giving access to
我们的用户在把他们
one of their most sensitive
最敏感的数据给予我们
data, and it is so important for
而确保我们怀着它
us to make sure that we're
赢得的尊重
treating it with the respect
来处理这些数据
that it deserves.
尤其重要
Next, with the brand-new workout
接下来 有了 Karim 介绍的
features Karim mentioned, we're
全新的体能训练特性
able to create seamless user
我们得以创造无缝的
experiences.
用户体验
With things like workout crash
有了像体能训练崩溃恢复的东西
recovery, we're able to really
我们能够呈现给
deliver an experience to our
用户真正期望的
users that they expect.
用户体验
And lastly, by implementing our
最后 通过使用新的
new Quantity series APIs, you're
Quantity series API
respecting the device's
你能够遵守设备的
capabilities and really making
能力并且真正确保
sure that, from start to finish,
从开始到结束
you are giving your users the
你都在给你的用户提供
best experience possible.
能力范围内的最佳体验
And as the health and fitness
由于健康和健身类
space and as workout apps just
和体能训练 App 持续
keep growing and users keep
增长 而且用户
using them more, we're so
用得越来越多
excited to see how these steps
我们很高兴看到这些东西
come together to create really
组合在一起能够创造
incredible experiences.
真正难以置信的用户体验
So for more information, please
更多信息 请参见
check out our developer
我们的开发人员文档
documentation, but we'd actually
但实际上如果今天能和你们当面
love to see you in person today.
聊聊 会更好
We're going to be at a lab today
今天下午 1 点到 3 点
from 1 to 3 as well as our
我们会有一个实验室
Health, Fitness, and Research
今天晚上 还有健康 健身和搜索聚会
and we'd love to answer any of
我们很乐意回答你们的
your questions, and hear your
任何问题 听听你们的
stories, and meet you in person.
故事 与你们面对面
We also want to mention that we
另外 我想说
have a brand-new features in
在 HealthKit 中我们有一些全新特性
HealthKit, and we'd love for you
我们很乐意你们都去
all to check out their talk,
看看他们的会议
Accessing Health Records with
用 HealthKit 访问
HealthKit.
健康数据
So thank you so much.
非常感谢各位
We're so excited to see what you
我们期待看到你们
all do with this.
用这些做的东西
Thank you.
谢谢
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］